(dan·yule whole·shoe) **UX + Visual Designer**

About Me

I'm a UX designer grounded in a fine arts background with experience in visual design, web design, and front end coding. My favorite thing is learning new skills and developing current ones. I'm at my happiest when I'm chewing on an interesting problem, working with a team of people who are equally committed to promoting a creative and uplifting atmosphere, and feel like I'm making a positive difference to someone, somewhere.

Skills

Figma, Sketch, Axure, Invision, Miro, Excalidraw, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Blender, Keynote, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Prototypes, Wireframes, Storyboards, UI Design, User Journey Maps, Comparative Analysis, Feature Cards, Usability Tests, Directed Storytelling, Annotated Wireframes, Information Architecture Maps, Kano Method, Heuristic Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, Kanban

Experience

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY – UX Support Instructor

June 2021 - January 2022

- Provided support to UX program students by coaching through UX client projects and deliverables.
- Assisted instructors with lectures, student questions, and creating assets.
- Critiqued and provided actionable feedback for student portfolios.

SPORTS STAR PHOTOGRAPHY – Photographer

February 2021 - June 2021

- Managed multiple concurrent tasks in a loud and fast-paced environment in various locations.
- Learned new skills and work flows on the job quickly, and taught those skills and flows to others.
- Organized large groups of children and adults while taking photos, managing paperwork, and adjusting equipment on the fly.

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY - UX Design Student

April 2020 - August 2020

- Worked on 5 projects for clients Foodsby, Saint Thomas More Catholic School, MnTech, Talk About Depression, and Prime
- Created wireframes, prototypes, architectural diagrams, conducted user research, synthesized research findings
- Distilled project activities and deliverables into succinct reports and presentations for clients
- Effectively managed time to complete complex projects on tight deadlines
- Collaborated with teams and interviewed test participants remotely

ProCraftr App

Self-Defined Project

- Created an interactive prototype for an app that will allow users to manage complex crafting projects
- Utilized Figma to digitize my wireframes, screen flow, and multi-touchpoint strategy user journey map, as well as create the interactive prototype
- Conducted two phases of research discovery research via comparative analysis, directed storytelling, and a feature sorting exercise, and evaluative research via usability tests

Yeeyo's Boutique

Group Client Project

- Communicated with the local small business owner on behalf of my team of designers to create a multi-touchpoint strategy for adapting her business model for the pandemic.
- Created information architecture, wireframes, and interactive prototype for an e-commerce website.
- Conducted competitive analysis of similar e-commerce businesses, comparative
 analysis of website platforms that would best suit the client's particular needs, and
 conducted a contextual inquiry of the client's physical store.

LIFETOUCH - Pre-Press Yearbook Editor February 2020 - April 2020

- Designed yearbook covers unique to each school, implemented customer requests in design creation, and integrated changes to designs reflecting customer feedback
- Learned to use in-house project management software in less than a week; aided my fellow contractors in learning to use the software

SHUTTERFLY - Production Designer August 2019 - December 2019

- Proofread and adjusted custom greeting cards, edited customer photos in Photoshop - assigned to team that executed advanced edit requests
- Mentored new employees in using in-house software, editing photos, making advanced edits, and interacting with customers
- Communicated with customers to ensure a quality experience and final product

SIGNET JEWELERS - Apprentice Bench Jeweler August 2018 - August 2019

- Perform minor gold and silver jewelry repairs, polish and inspect finished repairs
- Interpret and fulfill customer wishes in order to design custom jewelry, draft and/or illustrate 2D designs of custom jewelry based on dictation
- Act as liaison for interactions between repair shop and stores/clients

JUDITH KINGHORN STUDIO - Apprentice Bench Jeweler

February 2015 - August 2018

- Create gold and silver jewelry by hand based on artist's designs
- Stage and photograph jewelry, as well as edit images for web and print
- Create and maintain studio website and client database
- Manage booth at craft shows set up booth and jewelry displays, interact with customers

Education

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY
User Experience Design Certification
August 2020

MINNESOTA STATE UNIVERSITY MOORHEAD BFA, Studio Art, Illustration Emphasis, Art History Minor June 2014